<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Craig</title><link>https://cwr.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Craig</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cwr.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>So It Begins</title><link>https://cwr.io/posts/so-it-begins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cwr.io/posts/so-it-begins/</guid><description>Finally, I have published a website on my domains.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always had thoughts of what I&amp;rsquo;d do with a website, but also realized that no one is interested enough in my thoughts to come to a website to read them. Then I would realize that I would have to pay a hosting fee and deal with a lot of HTML/CSS to design it properly (and boy am I picky). That was always enough to convince me not to do it.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, I have published a website on my domains.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always had thoughts of what I&rsquo;d do with a website, but also realized that no one is interested enough in my thoughts to come to a website to read them. Then I would realize that I would have to pay a hosting fee and deal with a lot of HTML/CSS to design it properly (and boy am I picky). That was always enough to convince me not to do it.</p>
<p>At some point I learned about static site generators realized I could remove the cost barrier and some of the design barrier (with themes designed by others).</p>
<p>This site will serve as a place for me to collect any writing I decide to do (mostly guides, likely), as well as list all projects I&rsquo;m involved in with descriptions. I may put other stuff here eventually, too.</p>
<p>The source code for the entire site is <a href="https://github.com/abyss/abyss.dev">available on GitHub</a>.</p>
<h3 id="theme-and-design-goals">Theme and Design Goals</h3>
<p>I wanted to have two separate sites: one that I can keep for my online identity, and one that I can use as a professional portfolio in real life. Originally, I was expecting to do two separate sites.</p>
<p>However, I eventually came to the thought that I could use the same website, and with some use of variables I could have some content or links on either site. Also, given that my online handle is &ldquo;Abyss&rdquo;, I was amused by the idea that my online identity website would be &ldquo;dark mode&rdquo;, and my professional portfolio &ldquo;light mode&rdquo;.</p>
<h3 id="static-site-generator-hugo--theme">Static Site Generator: Hugo + Theme</h3>
<p>This site uses <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> as a Static Site Generator. If you&rsquo;re not familiar with it, essentially it allows me to write most of the site in Markdown and quickly compile to static HTML files. I chose it mostly because of it&rsquo;s popularity.</p>
<p>For a theme, I picked out <a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">hello-friend-ng</a> by Djordje Atlialp from the Hugo Theme&rsquo;s site. I picked it primarily because it had a light and dark mode, and had a nice minimalist-geek aesthetic.</p>
<p>Did I mention that I&rsquo;m picky? I wanted to change some things&hellip; so I did. The actual theme used by the site is <a href="https://github.com/abyss/hugo-theme-hello-abyss">hello-abyss</a>. More details about the differences in the README on GitHub.</p>
<p>I use Hugo Environments to use different configuration sets (merged with the <code>_default</code> configuration) to add different settings for each domain&rsquo;s build.</p>
<h3 id="build--hosting-github">Build / Hosting: GitHub</h3>
<p>When I push any changes to GitHub, the entire site is rebuilt using GitHub Actions. The sites are then hosted in two repositories that use GitHub Pages to serve.</p>
<p>Primarily, this is all on the back of <a href="https://github.com/peaceiris/actions-hugo">@peaceiris&rsquo; actions-hugo</a> and <a href="https://github.com/peaceiris/actions-gh-pages">actions-gh-pages</a>.</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s been incredibly fun building out everything for the sites, and I&rsquo;m incredibly pleased with the results. More is to come, as I plan to add a Projects page at the very least, and maybe a Tech page where I put the hardware and software I use and recommend. I also have some thoughts on things I&rsquo;d like to look different in the theme as well.</p>
<p>Thanks for checking out my page!</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>