<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Craig Reeder</title><link>https://cwr.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Craig Reeder</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cwr.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello Hugo</title><link>https://cwr.io/posts/hello-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cwr.io/posts/hello-hugo/</guid><description>Finally, a published site on my domains.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to keep an up to date website, but never wanted to spend money on hosting or website builders and wanted a relatively straight-forward management process.
That&amp;rsquo;s where Hugo came to the rescue. Being a static site generator, I am able to host it on GitHub Pages, for free, using a prebuilt theme! Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m picky, so I&amp;rsquo;ve modified the theme to my liking, contributing upstream when it made sense.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, a published site on my domains.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always wanted to keep an up to date website, but never wanted to spend money on hosting or website builders and wanted a relatively straight-forward management process.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s where Hugo came to the rescue. Being a static site generator, I am able to host it on GitHub Pages, for free, using a prebuilt theme! Of course, I&rsquo;m picky, so I&rsquo;ve modified the theme to my liking, contributing upstream when it made sense.</p>
<p>This site will serve as a place for collecting any writing I do, as well as list the projects I&rsquo;m involved in with descriptions. I may add other stuff down the line.</p>
<p>The source code for the entire site is <a href="https://github.com/abyss/abyss.dev">available on GitHub</a>.</p>
<h3 id="theme-and-design-goals">Theme and Design Goals</h3>
<p>I wanted to have two separate sites: one that I can keep slightly anonymized (for sharing online), and one that I can use as a professional portfolio in real life. Originally, I was expecting to do two separate sites.</p>
<p>However, through some clever tricks using Hugo environments, I am able to build the same site with slightly different choices. This ultimately means a shared code base between both sites, and dual posting all content.</p>
<h3 id="static-site-generator-hugo--theme-choice">Static Site Generator: Hugo &amp; Theme Choice</h3>
<p>This site uses <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> as a Static Site Generator. If you&rsquo;re not familiar with it, essentially it allows me to write most of the site in Markdown and quickly compile to a static HTML/CSS/JS website. I chose it mostly because of its popularity and ease of use.</p>
<p>For a theme, I started with <a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">hello-friend-ng</a> by Djordje Atlialp from the Hugo Theme&rsquo;s site. I picked it primarily because it had a light and dark mode, and had a nice minimalist-geek aesthetic.</p>
<p>I wasn&rsquo;t quite fond of every decision made by Djordje, which lead me to customizing the theme more and more. The theme the site now uses is <a href="https://github.com/abyss/hugo-theme-hello-abyss">hello-abyss</a>. More details about the differences can be found in the README on GitHub.</p>
<p>As mentioned before, I am using Hugo Environments to use different configuration sets (merged with the <code>_default</code> configuration) to add different settings for each domain&rsquo;s build.</p>
<h3 id="hosting--cicdcd-github--github-actions">Hosting &amp; CI/CD/CD: GitHub &amp; GitHub Actions</h3>
<p>When I push any changes to GitHub, the entire site is rebuilt using GitHub Actions. The sites are then hosted in two repositories that use GitHub Pages to serve.</p>
<p>Primarily, this is all on the back of <a href="https://github.com/peaceiris/actions-hugo">@peaceiris&rsquo; actions-hugo</a> and <a href="https://github.com/peaceiris/actions-gh-pages">actions-gh-pages</a>, which are well documented and easy to use.</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s been fun building out everything for the sites, and I&rsquo;m incredibly pleased with the results. There will surely be more to come, as I have a few plans for the site and theme.</p>
<p>Thanks for checking it out!</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>